大门前家庭欢乐集会 麻溜的
Family fun meeting by the front door, stat!
"麻溜的"意思就是马上
"Stat" means right now!
怎么啦
Ugh. What is it?
别理她 她一整天都心情不好
Ignore her. She's been in a bad mood all day.
卢克根本不在家
And Luke isn't home yet.
我就在这儿呢
Oh. I'm right here.
你刚刚上哪儿去了
Where were you?
这房子依然充满秘密啊
This house still holds its secrets.
你们应该很好奇我为什么叫你们过来
You're probably wondering why I called you all here.
-一点也不 -现在可以停止好奇
- Nope. - Well, stop your wondering...
我们不好奇
We're not wondering.
拭目以待 这个奇观吧
and behold.... this wonder!
我的天呐 不是吧
oh, my god! Seriously?
我卖了套房给独一无二的皮特·约翰逊
I sold a home to the one and only Pete Johnson.
世上只有一个皮特·约翰逊吗
There's only one Pete Johnson?
叫这名的加州顶级房车经销商就一个
Only one who's California's top R.V. dealer.
另有835个呢 要签下售车合同简直是噩梦
There's 835 others. Nightmare of a deal to paper.
所以这是要表达
Well, and this was his way of saying...
-感谢 -当然了
- Thank you. - Of course.
他付佣金了是不是
he paid a commission, too, right?
没错 他还说我随时都能把乔琳开出去
Yes. And he told me I could take Iolene out anytime.
没错 我给她起名字了
Yeah, I named her!
我们开这小骚车去海岸转转吧
Let's take this dirty girl for a spin up the coast!
-好耶 -太赞了 相当不错吧
- Yes! - Awesome! Pretty sweet, huh?
没错
Yeah!
我可以预见接下来会怎样了
I can see where this is going.
今年夏天 你 我和孩子们
This summer--you, me, the kids,
黄石国家公园
Yellowstone National Park.
这还只是辆维罗纳 他还让我开阿玛菲款的呢
And that's just the Verona, he offered me an Amalfi.
阿玛菲呀 克莱尔
An Amalfi, Claire!
那会让安布里亚像波特菲诺一样[意大利城市]
That makes the Umbria look like a Portofino!
他们不该称之为罗马帝国
Well, they should've called it the Roman,
因为这是我们要做的事情
'cause that's what we're about to be doin'.
我都听不懂你的意思了
I'm really not following you.
跟孩子们来一段10天的旅程
Ten days on the road with those kids?
"万万"不行
Winnebag-no.
我超讨厌菲尔搞这些
I hate it when Phil does this.
现在我只能唱黑脸
Now I have to be the bad guy
介入其中 粉碎他的"美妙"主意
who comes in and squelches his brilliant idea.
我说了不行 把那玩意儿从我家里牵出去
I said no. Get it out of my house.
好吧
Fine.
走吧 乔琳
Come on, Jolene.
好在 这一次
Fortunately, this time,
我不用再特意扫他的兴了
I don't have to be the wet blanket,
因为只要上海岸边小转一圈
Because even on just a short spin up the coast,
菲尔就会看到我每天都要面对的
Phil will see what I see every day--
孩子们一被关进车里
The transformation that happens
就会闹得天翻地覆
when our kids are locked in a moving metal box...
犹如被解锁出笼的海怪
The kraken that is unleashed.
我其实非常非常爱我的孩子们
I love my kids very, very much.
-你戳疼我了 -是啊 我知道 宝贝
- You're poking me. - Yeah, well, I know, sweetie.
但如果我不把发夹弄好
But I don't get these pins just right,
你的发髻就会在表演时散下来
your bun could fall out during your routine,
那样就会影响你的发挥
and it could mess you up.
好吧 来试看看
Okay, let's test it out.
好了
All right.
跳
Jump.
很好 转圈
Good. Spin.
来个碧昂斯的动作
Now give me Beyonce.
好了 我只能帮到这里了
Okay, I've done everything I can do.
接下来靠你自己了
It's up to you now.
我们家里出了个体操运动员
We have a gymnast in our family.
没错 莉莉去上体操班
Yeah, Lily goes to gymnastics class.
在短短一年内
In one short year,
我已见证了她从一个
I've seen her blossom from a little girl
完全不会翻跟斗的小姑娘
who couldn't do a somersault...
进步到现在 算是会了吧
into one who... kind of can.
是啊 以那标准来看 我们家里还有
Yeah, and by that standard, we also have a black belt,
柔道黑段 艺术天才 和首席芭蕾演员呢
art prodigy, and prima ballerina in our family, so...
但我们家里缺少
You know, what we don't have in our family
两位慈爱 支持的父亲
is two loving, supportive fathers.
我只是想强调她才5岁 明白嘛
I'm just saying, she's 5, you know?
你老是提醒她这点
And you never let her forget it.
-打扰一下 那是你女儿吗 -是啊
- Excuse me, is that your little girl out there? - It is.
-你帮她扎的头发 -是啊
- And you did her hair? - I did.
你能帮我女儿朱莉也做个一样的发型吗
Do you mind helping my Julie with hers?
你们是开敞篷车过来的吗
Oh, do you guys own a convertible?
-不是 -我无意评判
- No. - Oh, no judgment.
等莉莉表演完 我就帮你弄
Yeah, I'll get to work right when Lily's done.
不错 结尾的跳跃是新式的
Not bad. That little leap at the end--that's new.
她真的表现得好好
She's getting really good.
你最好给我拿出最好的表现来
You better bring your "A" Game.
天呐 小卡快瞧 莉莉第二了 9.2分
Oh, my god. Cam, look. Lily's in second place. 9.2.
我早跟你说了她是个体操运动员
I told you she's a gymnast.
分数这么高 她能进预选队了
With scores like that, she's gonna make pre-team.
你是说真的吗
Are you serious?
预选队 她能进预...什么是预选队
Pre-team? She could make pre-- what's pre-team?
克莱尔
Claire!
菲尔
Phil!
海莉
Haley!
卢克
Luke!
艾丽克斯
Alex!
歌洛莉亚 我们把全家人的名字都喊过三遍了
Gloria, we've been through the roster three times.
他们不在家
They're not home.
但他们的车在呢 能上哪儿去呢
But their cars are here. Where could they be?
谁知道这些人在搞什么
Who knows what these people do?
但我的书包在里面 杰
But my backpack is in there, Jay,
里面有我要在诗歌朗诵会上读的诗
My poem for my poetry reading.
别激动 难道你没在电脑上备份吗
Calm down. Didn't you back it up on your computer?
什么样的人会用电脑写诗啊
What kind of man writes poetry on a computer?
你该问 什么样的人还写诗啊
You could've ended that sentence after "Poetry."
进来 别问我怎么进的
Come in. And no questions.
我的书包不在楼上
My backpack wasn't upstairs.
那是什么
What's that?
克莱尔的朋友寄给她的明信片 叫瑞秋
Postcard from a friend of Claire's--Rachel.
"在科苏梅尔岛的地中海俱乐部享受人生呢"
"Living it up in Club Med Cozumel."
看来这人的婚姻是泡汤了
Looks like that marriage went down the drain.
另外有个更爆炸的消息
In other shocking news,
菲尔订了一份蹦床杂志
Phil subscribes to a trampoline magazine.
偷看别人的信件...
Going through other people's mail--
注意素质修养 杰
Keeping it classy, Jay.
妈 我的书包不在卢克房间
Mom, my backpack isn't in Luke's room.
我在这边也没看到
I don't see it in here, either.
我觉得那地方塞不下吧
I don't think it would fit in there.
我进来的时候它开着
Ay, this was open when I came in.
我就找片阿司匹林
I was just looking for an aspirin.
我刚刚似乎听到了什么动静
I thought that I heard some noises.
承认吧 你就是在窥探
So you were snooping?
这就算窥探了
Oh, so now it's snooping,
我只是想更了解我的家人
Wanting to know more about your family
翻翻他们的生活用品而已
by looking through their personal things?
不是就现在 打世界上有东西起你就这样
Not just now. Since the invention of things.
那是克莱尔做的布朗尼吗
Is that one of Claire's brownies?
不是 可好吃了 肯定是小卡做的
No, they're delicious. Must be Cam's.
-噢不 -别担心 还有呢
- Oh, no. - Don't worry. There's more.
不 我想起我的书包在哪里了
No! That's where my backpack is.
小卡送我和卢克回的家
Cam drove me and Luke home.
我肯定是落在他车里了
I must've left it in his car.
你最近怎么总是丢三落四的
Why are you so scattered lately?
他只是很紧张今晚的诗歌朗诵会
Aw, he's just nervous because of his poetry reading tonight.
但别担心 宝贝
But don't worry, papi.
我会去现场支持你的
I am going to be there to support you.
我不想我妈过去
I don't want my mom there.
我正在探索一些暗黑题材
I'm exploring some darker themes
我觉得她还没准备好接受
I'm not sure she's ready for,
我写的诗有《脐带》
Poems like "The umbilical noose,"
《名叫妈妈的监狱》
"A jail called mom,"
《窒息的本性》
"Smother nature."
她肯定会往她自己身上扯
She'll just find some way to make it all about her.
给乖女儿海莉把温度调到舒适的75度
And a toasty 75 degrees for daughter Haley.
知道不
You see,
维罗纳宝车能对温度进行对点调节 克莱尔
the Verona boasts individualized climate zones, Claire.
我完全可以把北极熊和兰花一起放车里
I could literally transport a polar bear and an orchid
而不用运两次
and not make two trips.
爸 我冻死了 感觉我这才1度
Dad, I'm freezing. It's, like, 1 degree back here.
上车6分钟 好戏开场了
Six minutes in, and it begins.
给 我从床上给你拿了条毯子
Here. Take the blanket from the bed.
谢谢老姐
Thanks, Kitten.
爸 能换首歌吗
Dad, can you change the music?
那还用说
Can I?
别啊别 这歌只会越来越吵
Oh, no. Oh, no, that's just getting louder.
这不好 糟透了
This isn't good. It's not good at all.
事实上这棒极了
Actually, it's kind of perfect.
是吧
Right?
大窗户 古典乐
The big windows, the classical music.
跟在电影里一样
It's like we're in a movie.
开大点声 帅哥
Turn it up, handsome.
听你的
You got it!
显然一时的新奇劲儿推迟了必然的闹剧
Obviously, the novelty of the situation was delaying the inevitable.
但我不想在去黄石公园的半路上
But I didn't want to get halfway into a trip to Yellowstone
菲尔才幡然醒悟
before Phil discovered
他这是给孩子们造了多大的孽
what malevolent hellspawn we have for children...
我对孩子们是真爱
Whom I love very much.
艾丽克斯 宝贝 你的毛衣好好看
Alex, honey, that's a cute sweater.
貌似海莉也有一件差不多的
Doesn't Haley have one like that?
就是她的
Oh, it actually is hers.
-我走之前从她衣柜顺的 -真的
- I took it from her closet before we left. - Really?
抱歉姑娘们 没想搞得你们不愉快的
Ooh. Sorry, girls. Didn't mean to start a whole thing.
我真不能忍 你穿我的衣服总是更好看
I am so sick of you always looking better in my clothes.
从什么时候起就这样了啊
When did that happen?
你一点都不介意吗
You're okay with this?
没事 她想穿什么穿什么
Oh, yeah. She can wear whatever she wants
反正我也穿了六个月了
After I've had it for six months.
或者你买件类似的 就自然送给我了
Or I get it automatically if you buy anything that looks like it.
感觉真是不错呢 是吧队友们
This just feels right. Huh, team?
事实上 我之前还想着
Matter of fact, I was thinking
我们一家子夏天可以驱车去黄石公园呢
we could all drive up to Yellowstone this summer.
但我现在提议
But I say,
我们开着这宝贝蛋跨越东西海岸吧
Let's take this beeyotch ocean to ocean!
-那太棒了 -赞啊
- That'd be cool! - Awesome!
那就说定啦
We're doing it!
菲尔 小心
Phil, the road!
我不知道我按了哪个按钮
I don't know what button I just pressed,
但真是爽死我了
But that was amazing.
我的书包肯定不在车里
My backpack's definitely not in there.
他们也不接电话
Well, they're not picking up their phone.
他肯定是带进屋了
He must've brought it inside.
抱歉 孩子 看来你只能自认倒霉了
Sorry, kid, looks like you're out of luck.
进来
Come!
他们难道都没装个防盗警报器吗
Don't they have a burglar alarm?
少废话
Ay, please.
好了大家 我们分头行动
Okay, everybody, split up and search.
杰 你去卧室找
Jay, you look in the bedroom.
我才不去基佬们的卧室呢
I'm not looking in their bedroom.
好吧
Fine.
妈 我的背包可不会在小卡的包里
Mom, I don't think my backpack is in Cam's bag.
我只是替他把包合上而已
I was just closing it for him.
我 听到有动静
I... heard a noise.
看起来像他们办过一场小派对
Looks like the guys threw a little party.
我注意到了
I noticed.
他们都把客人专用香皂拿出来了
They brought out the guest soaps.
你这是来了多久了
How long have you been in here?
嘿 这是菲尔开公司的时候
Hey. This is that bottle of wine
我给他买的那瓶酒
I bought Phil when he started his company.
克莱尔的唇膏印还留在这些酒杯上
And Claire's lipstick is on many of these wineglasses.
看图猜词 他们昨晚是游戏之夜
Pictionary. They had game night?
可我们向来都参加游戏之夜的呀
But we always go to game night.
他奶奶的 他们抛弃了我们
Son of a bitch. They snubbed us.
找到了
Found it!
肯定有好多人来玩
There must've been a dozen players.
胡娇也来了
Pepper was here.
可胡娇是爱我的呀
But Pepper loves me.
好了 搞定
Okay, she's all set.
我敢说你在馆里绝找不到更紧的发髻了[屁股]
I defy you to find a tighter bun in this gymnasium.
你完全可以换种说法的
Lot of different ways you could've said that.
祝你自由体操好运 宝贝
Oh, and good luck on your floor routine, sweetie.
但你不用运气也很厉害了
Not that you need it.
那是艾比
That's Abby.
她是班里最厉害的
She's the best in class.
她是我们的竞争对手
Oh. She's our competition.
我从没这么想要打败一个小孩过
I've never wanted to beat a kid so badly.
你没听到我说的吗
Are you not hearing these?
没有吗 好吧
No? Okay.
莉莉在平衡木上了
Oh, Lily's on the beam.
我好担心她的下马动作
I'm nervous about her dismount.
你说过她着地时能站稳 是吧
You said that she could stick the landing, right?
是的 只要她调整呼吸 依靠基本功
Yeah, as long as she breathes, relies on her training,
待在平衡木上
and stays in the zone.
我们是在说她要从6英寸的木头上下来
We are talking about her stepping off a 6-inch beam.
而且不摔倒 是的
And not falling. Right.
我不得不承认
I have to admit.
看到莉莉这么棒激发了我内心的一些情绪
Seeing Lily do so well brought out something in me.
是作为家长 自己的孩子不只是参与
The pride of being a parent of a child
而是表现卓越的骄傲感
who wasn't just participating but thriving.
好了 她要下马了
Okay, here comes her dismount.
稳住 莉莉 稳住
Stick it Lily. Stick it!
她站稳了
she stuck it!
She stuck it!
如果她的平衡木得分最高
If no one beat my daughter's score on the beam,
她就能进预选队了
She would make pre-team.
她就将成为健将中的一员
She'd be one of the elite.
骄傲感这玩意儿 真有意思
Funny thing, pride.
听说它产生于
They say it goeth before the...
摔下来 摔下来
Fall. Fall.
-摔倒 -米奇尔 我能听到你
- Fall. - Mitchell, I can hear you...
-什么 -在为一个小女生的摔倒加油
- What? - Rooting for a little girl to fall.
如果我能听到 别人也能听到
If I can hear you, other people can hear you.
好棒
Yes!
我不知道自己为什么喝倒彩 抱歉
I don't know why I said that. I don't--I'm sorry.
是的 他不是那个意思
Yeah, he didn't mean it.
-我不是那个意思 -他是太投入了
- I didn't mean it. - No, um, he just got caught up.
我们都知道
And, uh, you know,we all know
比赛让人疯狂
competition makes people do crazy things.So...
你看看 她的发髻在自由体操时散了
Look at this! Her bun fell apart during the floor exercise.
头发挡住了眼睛 动作都没法做完
Her hair got in her eyes and she couldn't even finish!
你故意的
You did it on purpose!
-不是 -老爸们
- No! - Daddies!
我是第一名哦
I'm in first place.
耶 真棒
Yay. That's great.
你得罪他们了吗
Did you offend them?
我 他们都很爱我
Me? They love me.
我们能走了吗 我今晚还要诗朗诵呢
Can we go now? I have a poetry reading tonight.
说到这个
And speaking of that,
-你们确定真的要去 -没道理啊
- Are you sure you guys really want-- - It makes no sense.
我们向来是每场派对的灵魂人物
We're always the life of every party.
可能他们没邀请你们
Maybe they didn't invite you
是因为你们是一对窥探狂
because you're a couple of snoops?
够啦 老好人先生
Okay, Mr. Goody two-shoes.
正常父母都会欣赏这一点
A trait normal parents would value.
杰 我觉得关于他 你说得对
Jay, I think you're right about him.
他作为一名小少年 最近太过于正直
He's been too good lately for a teenager.
那不正常
It's not normal.
我觉得这个世界就要
I am afraid that the world is going to--
天啊 这也太过分了
Oh, hell, no. This is too far. Ay.
看这个
Look at this.
那难道是...
Is that supposed to be...
就是我们俩
That's us.
我们不只是被抛弃了
Not only do we get blown off,
他们还拿我们当笑料
now they're making fun of us.
我要给他们留个信
Well, I'm just gonna leave them a little message.
依我看
As far as I'm concerned,
他们都可以
They can all...
马嘴巴 好题目
Horse mouth! That's a good one!
不是 "马嘴"可不是个短语
No, "Horse mouth" Is not an expression.
你看不懂吗
You can't get this?
看 驴子
Look. Donkey.
-那可一点不像驴子 -看这驴耳朵
- That's not a donkey. - Look at the ears.
好吧 驴嘴
Okay. Donkey mouth!
你猜得太烂了
That's a terrible guess.
你画得太烂了
That's a terrible drawing!
他们不邀请我们 就因为你玩得太烂
We weren't invited because you stink at this game.
至少我会画画
At least I can draw!
打扰一下 请签收一下
Excuse me. Just need a signature.
拿来吧
Yeah, sure.
好吧
Okay.
签好了
Here we go.
拿去吧 谢谢
There. Thank you.
好的
Yep.
那不是签名 你这是画了只猫
That's not a signature. You drew a cat.
谢你八辈祖宗了啊
Thank you.
一派完美和谐的景象
Perfect freaking harmony.
我突然想明白了
That's when it hit me.
也许并不是封闭的车内空间
Maybe it's not the cold confines of a moving vehicle
让我的孩子们表现出顽劣捣蛋的一面
that brings out the worst in my kids.
而是我 让他们爆发出顽劣捣蛋的一面
Maybe I bring out the worst in them
因为没有风趣有爱的菲尔
when there's no fun-lovin' Phil around
来中和我的负能量
to neutralize my toxins.
那让我羞愧得无地自容
I was in a full shame spiral.
有蜜蜂
Aah! A bee!
可就在这时 好事来了
And then something wonderful happened.
让我来
I got it!
-你个蠢货 -杀了它
- You idiot! - Kill it!
不 别杀
No, don't!
你不知道蜜蜂是濒危动物吗
Haven't you heard of colony collapse?
蜜蜂快要灭绝了
Bees are endangered!
好啦孩子们 别乱动
Okay, guys, stand still.
只要你们不动 它就看不见你们
They can't see you if you're not moving.
它冲我来了
It's coming near me!
你把我当蜜蜂吗
Do I look like a bee?!
不 是我出手失误
No, that was an accident!
那我也失误一回
Well, so is this!
大家淡定
Everyone remain calm!
我这就打开双棚天窗
I'll just open up the double-tilt swiss skylight
气流会把蜜蜂
and the airflow will pull
-抽出去的 -又来一只蜜蜂
- the bee out of-- - Aah! There's another bee now!
我们肯定闯进了蜂窝
We must be near its cave!
老天啊 简直是蠢疯了
Oh, my god! There's so much stupid in here!
好啦 我这就停车
All right, I'm pulling this thing over.
开成雨刷了
Those are the wipers.
克莱尔 帮帮忙
Claire, say something!
孩子们 别闹了
Kids, stop, please.
嘿 每天都有航班去黄石公园呢
Hey, there are daily flights to Yellowstone.
你把我衣服扯烂了
Aah! You ripped my sweater!
是我的衣服 你根本就不该穿
My sweater, which you shouldn't even be wearing!
-把衣服还给我 -航班在盐湖城短暂停留
- Get off of my sweater! - Short layover in Salt Lake.
你就一点忙都不帮吗
Are you really not gonna do anything?
菲尔 你肯定早就知道会这样
Oh, Phil, you must have known this was gonna happen.
我听得出来你的语气 你想证明什么
I know that tone. You're making a point.
你现在早早发现他们的本性
It's better that you find out who they are now
总比你穿越半个国家了才发现要好
than when you're halfway across the country.
好吧 看来我真是太幼稚
Well, I guess I'm just a naive boob
还以为我们家相亲相爱呢
who thought we liked each other!
显然 这一切都是我的奢望
Obviously, it was too much to ask
一家人开开心心地出游
to think that we could take one magnificent trip
享受豪华的房车之旅
in a tricked-out, state-of-the-art R.V.
去看太平洋的海上日落
to see the sun dancing off the Pacific.
我真是太强人所难了
What a huge ask!
我受不了大家用这种眼光看着我们
I can't stand the way everyone's starting at us.
我懂 就像我们看别人遛鸟时
Yeah, I know. It's the way we look at people
那种鄙视的眼神
who walk with their pet birds.
小美女来啦
There she is!
小宝贝 祝你平衡木成功哦
Hey, good luck on your balance beam routine, sweetie.
-你会很棒的 -我永远赢不了莉莉
- You're gonna do great. - I'll never beat lily.
你当然能 因为你是超级小明星
Of course you will, because you're a superstar!
你女儿也是个天才啊 我是她的粉丝
And your daughter's a genius. I am such a fan. Such a fan.
-好吧 你这样太夸张了 -我是迫不得已
- Okay, now you're overcompensating. - I have to!
你也看见我刚刚有多过分
You saw what a monster I was out there.
这恰恰是我恨我爸的一点
This--this is the exact thing I always hated in my dad,
他总认为不择手段的强硬真汉子才能赢
that ugly macho testosterone drive to win,
今天我自己却也踩进这怪圈了
and today it has flowered in me.
小卡 我今天一定要打破怪圈
Well... No, this ends today, Cam.
我绝不能让莉莉也受到同样的影响
I am not passing this on to Lily.
其实 这也不能全怪你
Well, it's not all on you. You know,
我在想 我可能确实故意弄坏了艾比的发型
I'm beginning to think maybe I did sabotage Abby's hair.
我没用定型喷雾 没来个碧昂斯范儿
I didn't spray. I didn't Beyonce.
我简直给她梳了个定时炸弹在头上
I basically built a ticking time bun.
好吧
Well...
你还好吧
Are you okay?
不好
No.
-我头发扯着疼 -我帮你弄一下
- My hair hurts. - I'll fix it.
我们找莉莉去吧
We should find Lily.
你们看见你家女儿干嘛了吗
Did you see what your daughter just did?
莉莉 你把朱莉的发夹拔下来了吗
Uh... Lily, did you pull the pins out of Julie's hair?
是的 她摔了
Yeah, she fell.
好吧
Oh. Okay, um...
大家能听我说两句吗
I--could I get everyone's attention for just a moment?
我们觉得 我家女儿刚刚的行为
We consider what our daughter just did
违背了体操运动的体育精神
to be an embarrassment to the sport of gymnastics.
我向你们保证 那绝对不是我们教的
I assure you, she did not learn this from us.
而且我们认为 这是弱者的表现
And as far as we are concerned, that is a sign of weakness...
不是胜利者该有的行为 而是
Not the way a winner behaves, but the way...
-失败者的行为 -失败者的行为
- A loser behaves. - A loser behaves.
走吧莉莉 我们去拿你的护掌和护腕
Come on, Lily. Let's get your grips and tiger paws.
-你得暂停比赛 -对 要多停一会
- You're going to a time-out. - Yeah. A nice long one.
我进预选队了
I made pre-team,
但我的爸爸们只能在外面观看
and my daddies get to watch from outside.
-必须在100英尺之外 -我们在申诉
- No closer than 100 feet. - But we're appealing.
莉莉太棒了
Yay, Lily!
杀死小鸡 酥炸鸡条
Kill the chicken! Chicken fingers!
鸽子人
Pigeon man!
鸽子人 鸽子人
Pigeon man? Pigeon man.
你看到了吧 托尼 不是我的错
You see, Tony, it's not me.
你会邀请她去游戏之夜吗
Would you invite her to game night?
我还是先走吧
I'm gonna go now.
那些要求隔天送达的人都不好伺候
They're kinda sticklers about the next-day delivery thing.
一鸟在手[已成定局]
Bird in the hand!
这就对了
There you go.
她要再慢点 就堪比美国邮政了
Any slower, she'd be the U.S. Mail,
你说是吧
am I right?
这笑话在我们仓库肯定笑倒一大片
That's gonna kill at the warehouse.
看见没 你才是问题
You see? You are the problem.
但你作弊了 我看见你偷瞄那张纸了
Except you cheated. I saw you look at the paper.
我就说嘛
I knew it.
你也好不到哪里去
You're no better.
大吼大叫 盛气凌人
All the screaming and bullying.
问题不是为什么你们没被邀请
The question isn't why you two weren't invited.
而是为什么以前有人愿意邀请你们
It's why you're ever invited.
顺便说一句 这画根本与你们无关
And by the way, this isn't even about you.
藏宝 箱
Treasure... Chest.
我们能不能把这收拾干净 赶紧离开
Now can we clean this place up and go?
说来有趣
Funny story.
我妈妈和杰其实被邀请了
My mom and Jay were invited.
小卡在学校把邀请函交给我
Cam gave me the invitation at school,
我把这事忘了
and I forgot about it.
但我怎么能在刚训完话之后就说出实情呢
But how could I tell them right after I'd shamed them?
我得毁灭证据
I had to cover my tracks.
没错 杰 我是作弊了
It's true, Jay. I cheated.
每次在游戏之夜我都会小作弊一下
I cheat a little bit every time that we come to the game night.
我觉得上次米奇发现了
I think Mitch saw me the last time,
所以他们不想再跟我们玩了
and that's why they don't want to play with us anymore.
你为什么要作弊
But why would you do that?
我不知道
I don't know!
也许我不想让你认为我笨
Maybe because I don't want you to think that I am not smart.
我绝不会那么认为
I would never think that.
再说 这其实是我的错
And besides, it's my fault, anyway.
孩子说得对 我太争强好胜
The kid is right. I'm too competitive.
玩快艇骰子输了一回
Lost a game of yahtzee once.
那些骰子现在还被我挂在墙上
The dice are still on the wall.
但至少你没有作弊
Yeah, but at least you're not a cheater.
我觉得自己真是个驴嘴巴
I feel like such a donkey mouth.
爹妈 我有事情要告诉你们
Guys, there's something you should know.
妈妈的教堂今晚举办棋盘问答游戏之夜
It's trivial pursuit night at mom's church.
我不想让你们错过我的诗歌朗读会
I hate for you to miss my poetry reading,
但或许你们可以去教堂
but maybe you could head down there,
培养一下公平竞争的体育精神
work on your sportsmanship,
你们就不会那么自责了
And you will feel better about yourselves.
你确定我不去你一个人能行吗
Are you sure you're going to be okay without me there?
是的 妈妈 妈妈 我上车等你们
Yes, mother. Mother. I'll be in the car.
我的过分好胜是从我爸那继承的
I get this damn competitive streak from my old man.
幸好我没有把这传给米奇尔
It's a miracle I didn't pass it down to mitchell.
真高兴我们能把这怪到父母头上
I love that we can blame our parents.
我母亲是我见过最爱作弊的大骗子
My mother was the biggest cheater I've ever known.
她以前特爱窥探我们的事
And she used to snoop on everything that we did.
杰 看看这个
Ay. Jay, look at this.
我们的邀请函
Our invitation.
他们肯定是忘给我们了
They must have forgot to give it to us.
不对 我刚进来就检查过这包
No. I checked this bag when we got here,
-当时不在里面 -为什么你总是
- and it wasn't there. - Why are you always--
你知道的 我有问题
'Cause you know I have a problem.
这是曼尼干的
This was Manny.
他忘了给我们
He forgot to give it to us,
然后就想偷偷地塞进去
and then he came and tried to sneak it in there.
他干嘛不直接告诉我们
Why wouldn't he just tell us?
也许因为他不想让我们去朗读会
Maybe because he doesn't want us to go to the reading.
所以他才一直说教堂和棋盘游戏的事
That's why he was talking about the church and the game.
他把我们耍了
He was working us.
看来他也不是个老好人
Guess he's not too much of a goody two-shoes.
不 他是个爱撒谎 搞诡计的小坏蛋
No. He's a lying, scheming little sneak.
真不愧是我儿子
That's my son.
我们的好儿子
Our son.
我从没见过爸爸发那么大火
I've never seen dad freak out like that before.
我感觉糟透了
I feel terrible.
一部分是我的错
Oh, it's partly my fault.
我引诱你们吵架 以显示我的先见之明
I goaded you guys into a fight to prove a point.
我为什么总是要赢
Why do I always have to win?
我是怎么变成这种人的
How did I get this way?
那车是你的吗
That you?
是的
Yeah.
-那车是你的吗 -是的
- You? - Yep.
你车里有几个小孩
How many kids in yours?
感觉像是30个
Felt like 30.
我有4个
I got four.
不过我打算把其中两个尽早轰出家门
But I'm thinking of emancipating two of them early.
但愿你们有香烟或酒
Tell me one of you has cigarettes or a flask.
不好意思 兄弟
Sorry, buddy.
我经历过各种情绪[州]
I've been through every state--
抑郁 紧张 阿肯色州
Depressed, catatonic, Arkansas.
我想过干脆在布莱斯峡谷国家公园假死算了
I considered faking my own death in Bryce Canyon National Park.
你们去过吗 不可错过哦
Have you been? Not to be missed.
我会错过 我会完全错过
I'm gonna miss it. I'm missing every bit of it.
我不会在那辆"移动精神病院"里再待一秒
I'm not spending another second in that rolling asylum.
可怜的家伙 上路多久了 几周吗
Poor guy. How long you been on the road? Couple weeks?
几天
Couple days?
爸正在那边跟超级可怜虫抱团呢
Dad's in the middle of a super sad dude hug.
我们真是令他失望了
We really disappointed him.
也许我们应该咬牙忍忍
Yeah, maybe we should just suck it up
今年暑假去杰里斯通公园吧
and go to Jellystone this summer.
慢着 所以爸才弄了这辆车吗
Wait. That's why dad got this thing?
今年暑假我不能去旅行
I-I can't go on a trip this summer.
-为什么 -我有
- Why? - I've...
-我有事 -不行 快说什么事
- I've got stuff. - Huh? No. What stuff?
-我不想说 -卢克
- I don't want to talk about it. - Luke.
暑期班 我的初级代数挂科了
Summer school. I'm failing pre-algebra.
-你为什么没说 -我不知道
- Why didn't you say something? - I don't know.
我觉得好蠢
I feel stupid.
你知道有她在前面做榜样是什么感觉吗
You know what it's like to follow her?
所以老师看着我
All the teachers look at me
都觉得我像是无理数余数
and think that I'm some kind of irrational remainder.
-我这样说对吗 -不对
- Did I use that right? - No.
该死
Dang it.
你为什么不问我呢 我可以辅导你
But why didn't you ask me? I would've tutored you.
我试过了 不过你总是待在你的房间里
I tried, but you were always off in your room
或是家里的角落打电话
or some corner of the house on the phone.
你最近总是和谁讲电话
Yeah, who have you been talking to so much lately?
-亚伦吗 -亚伦是谁
- Aaron? - Who's Aaron?
事实上有两个男生 亚伦和艾历克斯
Actually, it's two boys-- Aaron and Alex.
-两个男生 -还有一个和你同名
- Oh, two boys. - A boy named Alex likes you?
我知道 好诡异
Yeah, I know. It's weird.
但我朋友安娣 "女"字旁的 是个女生
But my friend Andi with an "I"-- she's a girl--
-也喜欢艾历克斯 -男艾历克斯吗
- Also liked Alex. - The boy?
当然是男的 我不会用第三人称来说自己
Yes, the boy. I don't refer to myself in the third person.
-我以为亚伦是第三人 -不
- I thought Aaron was the third person. - No.
总之 我觉得脚踩两条船挺酷的
Anyway, I thought I was cool juggling two boys at once,
但是
But...
他们在同一天甩了我
They both ended up dumping me on the same day.
甜心 那太可怕了
sweetie, that's awful.
我怎么会不知道这些事
How did I not know this was happening?
你最近太忙了
You've been really busy lately,
你要翻新房子
like with flipping that house.
而且我并不想谈这个
And plus I didn't really want to talk about it,
因为说起来怪丢人的
because it's kind of embarrassing.
比不上挂掉以"初级"为名字的课程丢人
Not as embarrassing as failing a class that starts with "Pre."
-宝贝 -你们想好受些吗
- Baby... - You guys wanna feel better?
我今早面试了湖人队的啦啦队员
I auditioned to be a Laker girl this morning.
-什么 真的吗 -不是吧
- What? You did? - No way.
我小时候上过舞蹈课
I took all those dance classes when I was younger,
我也不知道 我最近想搞清楚
and, I don't know. I've been trying to figure out
我这辈子想做什么
what I want to do with my life,
我在网上看到他们有公开选拔赛
So I saw online that there were open tryouts,
-所以我就去了 -然后呢
- so I went down there. - And?
我是最新的湖人队啦啦队长 妈
I'm the new head Laker girl, mom.
真是场灾难 我是其中最差劲的
It was a disaster. I was the worst one there.
我甚至记不住整套表演动作
I couldn't even get through my routine.
你们有一套表演动作吗
You have a routine?
帕特 希斯 你们让我有勇气回去
Pat, Heath, you guys have given me the courage to go back in there,
勇敢面对我妻子
stand up to my wife,
告诉她 她一直是对的
and tell her she was right all along.
一路顺风 菲尔
Happy trails, Phil.
希斯
Heath?
我还想继续待一会儿
I might just stay here a while.
菲尔 菲尔 我得告诉你一些事
Phil. Phil, I have to show you something.
别得意洋洋 我知道了
Don't gloat. I get it.
我尝试令家人亲近
I keep trying to push this family closer together,
-但他们各自需要空间 -不
- but they need their space. - No, no, no.
我们的空间太多了
We have too much space.
被困在一间屋子里却令我们
Being in trapped in one room has forced us
能彼此交谈
to actually talk to one another,
我发现了孩子们的一些不可思议的事情
and I have found out some incredible things about our kids.
等等 不可思议的好吗
Wait. Incredible good?
你说呢
You tell me.
我的天
Oh, my god.
梦想成真 我甚至不需要了解来龙去脉
Dream come true! I don't even need context!
这是什么情况
What is this?!
-我们继续旅行吗 -只要乔琳没意见就行
- So our trip's back on? - We're in if Jolene's in.
-快点来吧 -好耶
- Come on. Do it! - Yeah!
为什么我就是不会呢
Why can't I get this?
你需要集中精神 心无杂念
You just gotta focus. Clear your mind.
放轻松 进入状态 你会的
Loosen up. Get in the zone. You know this.
我们一起来过一遍
Okay, we're gonna walk through this together,
一步步的
step by step.
五六七八
Five, six, seven, eight...
一二三四
One, two, three, four,
-五六七八 -56.1加上或减去8.25
- Five and six, seven and eight... - 56.1 plus or minus 8.25.
-这是第一题 -一二三四
- That's the first one. - One, two, three, four,
-五六二五 -第二题 X加上2除以4
- Five, six, two, five-- - Okay, number 2-- X plus 2 over 4
-等于3加3 -减 见鬼
- equals 3 plus 3-- - Minus-- damn it,
艾丽克斯 小声点行吗
Alex, do you mind?
我们这里正在做正事呢
We're doing something important here.
好了
Okay.
再来一遍 从头开始 就当旁边没人
Once more. From the tippy, like nobody's watching.
五六七八 一二
Five, six, seven, eight. One two...